The consent agenda, and if there are no objections to any of those items would ask for motion. Motion approved in a second?
Local...
Question ...
That takes us item 16 which is approved at November 3rd and contract C16-46 with can facilitate the throughlaed plan Tyler
Yes sir
With the separation of public works and Public Utilities, we moved all
The managers myself. We move down to Operation Center so that
Copy or Down there this is adding in a copy
To answer the total contract
Okay
Any questions?
And we need a motion
Approved the agenda
A second
Roll call
All right
Thank you
I don't know 17 is a lecture resolution for fiscal year 2016-2017
It's lengthy resolutions, repayments
So not going to read the whole thing just point out that there will be filing people
Is The First Week in February from the Minis Polo offices which we'll include
The North East, Northwest and Southeast Ward
I get there right in
Yes
If anyone is interested
In filing for Council positions
Please go find
You will throw the county clerk's office
The filing period starts on that Monday February 1st
It's Monday Tuesday Wednesday and then there is a withdrawal
Period if someone changes their mind
That the following Thursday in Friday
Dave was anything else I need to touch
No, don't think so mayor
Again just repeat it as
North East Ward
Northwest ward
We have a motion to approve of resolution
I'm making motion to approve the amended copy
Not on in our packet with this one
So
Just To be clear
Got one of The Hessen changes
You can see it here, but that's okay
What you'll find mayor is
That i think someone along
In 2015 calendar
The version or presenting to you for this position
Or vote tonight
Would show the following period of Monday February 1st Tuesday
Feb. 2nd and Wednesday, february 3rd
And withdrawal in contest
February 4th
Friday, february 5
I'm going call it
Redline version
Yes sir
Okay
All right
Second
Okay
All right
Item 18, resolution supporting february 3rd housing consideration for a text credit award
For a new affordable housing which is up to 20 single family dwellings
Located on infill lots within the original town side of city in Miami
And after 24 years with In The Harvest time tabernacle building
For Opaloma, affordable housing partners LLC
I think we talked a little bit about this
Our last meeting of last year
Yes it was on our December 8th meeting
We actually talk to better than Great Lake
Tonight what Tammy Creason is going
To be doing
Basically showing how the general concept has now been formalized into
The resolution and will be presented
And again our recommendation is still very much to approve of
We think it's right in line with
Our comprehensive plan and what has identified for both historical
Housing redevelopment
I'd like point out that some you might have seen an article on K.O.M last night
About the number
They can homes we haven't my animal
A lot
This a steel item
It draws
A lot of attention to people when you look at Facebook post and things like this
It's such a good step forward
To see somebody coming in
Starting developing new housing on our town
Is there a presentation relating
On the mitten Tammy, I'm going
Going into an important quick presentation
So Tammy be sure about what infill lots are
Probably well but just make sure he touched all that
Absolutely thankyou guys so much
I didn't kind of shorten this up from the last presentation that we had
But, but
The project basically consists two components all
Of which are going to be in
In
So our headquarters base is gonna
Be
Tabbinacol
Which has a historic mining
Stange building
We've submitted
To
Workplace on the National Register
We've kind of worked with our comprehensive plan
And we're calling this project root 66 landing
Trying to embody that downtown spirit
So,
The historic building which will be 24 apartments
These two seniors
In
Downtown area
We've got a community space
I'm going to show you in just a minute
And then the second component of that is
To meet
The greatest demographic and need
As, with city
On these infill lots
In do new single family homes
So there are three bedroom
Two bathrooms
Two carcass
A lot of character and kind
To have that historic appearance to them
So all the lots are going
And we've got a list
Of
That downtown historical building
We're working with
The county owned
Worked this
To identify those
Upto 20
As what were asking for
After an allocation
If
We're working with
On a walk
To identify
Exactly what those 20 are
Right now the ones in your packet
Or all city owned county own lots
That had blinded housing on it
It was torn down
Whether this is otherwise owned
I'll quickly show you
And just second
On
We've got some of these laws being owned by the county
David and I have had a
Discussion with Commissioner girls
And we will
Have to work
With The County Commission that has happened in
In
To us they are more than happy
Transfer
For those projects or happy
That
Some details
We have a lot of
The
So the idea would be
Will submit our application to
Oh, which is local home housing
That competes
Of in next couple months with projects
Throughout
The state including your other
Our
Early indications on what those
Ranking and Scorings are
And as soon we have some early identification
We can start working
On a lot of the specific details
But
The single family home
To our three bedroom homes
Two bath
This storm building
We've got
A library kind of a formal area
To be worked with some
The downtown organizations to do kind
Museums and pictures
Different things
In that main entry for you
Sticking
We've got a shopahawar core
With community tables in space
And all the spaces
Offices, everything
As communities
And then the fours two through five
All
Me or each other
In our combination of one and 2 bedroom apartment
The majority are in
Two bedrooms
There's 22 bedroom
On a beach
Of those
And we talked about it
All these will have their modern finishes
We're working to revitalize that
We want to put these houses in small groups
And the nominations on some of
These streets that you guys are working
To clean up your life
You start raising out the standards
Compliance and code enforcement
Creating around what this standard going forward
So we're really excited about
That opportunity
It could be a part
Most
As an impact
Our individual lots and their info
But one
We talked about a little bit in the office
And we want to create that visual
Momentum
In downtown
So, with my partner at the office
It's here tonight
At Dean
And so
We had some great conversations
And some of them are working
We used to make the greatest impact
The one thing that I think everybody can compromise
Through those meetings
Everybody was happy with this
This is a city owned vacant lot
It's unpaid
Its contiguous two existing parking lots
So, it would be
The back side of chapters
There were parking lots overflow
In downtown
That was included in the city owned lot
It's included with a package
And so that would give us four houses
Right-knorrow
You're creating kind of visual impact
What is seen or it will be
Kindred created to get into
Housing and Time to the Downtown retail
So here we are
Everybody, there were lots
This could have been
The sort building
It's a little bit of a kind
A couple of people
And you can see these are all in half of my
You know, two or three here
Two and one there
So just spreading those out
Anywhere we could get
We think that created to make us momentum
But then the downtown
To be able
That would come into your company
There is a special initial list
Of what those locations would be
But up to 20 homes
I think this actually represents 18 homes
but just kind of that initial plan
In Glender, none other these are fly areas
Sure.
So obviously we'd have
To build up
Yes
As long as you're too young
And Glenn and when he talked about 30D
It's a part of 30d
And it's just that they will have to
Compatible
Yeah, I got to be a checkable
That could mean yeah
We talked about this
We did not go through the road
So
To tell us what you guys want
Last time my very enthusiasm
Could we took up
A lot of your times
Or didn't do anything
But its been
Meeting with downtown
We have some extremely enthusiastic business
And we're really excited about the opportunity to be a part of that
Just do it everything
Can make this as competitive as possible
So, you can get some momentum
You know on your face too and see what
See What
Do something
Anything
Any questions?
I kind
According to our comprehensive plan
To start getting this type of development
And a central business district
Again, I've worked with programs like
This and the past
They're real thing if we get
The approval
With tax credits
If you mean lot
Good things for downtown my end
There may be help
We will come back
About essentially committing public property
To what at first glance may appear to be a private use
But the law of economic development
As it's been developed in The Oklahoma Courts
It makes this possible
Provided that certain conditions are met
And I will certainly make sure
Those conditions are met
Explaining back
When time comes
Okay, so
We have a resolution specifically the past
Just don't need to be hard copy
Reducer
The part of that one in your path
It will impact the government
So with our knowledge of questions
I would entertain emotion
To approve the resolutions
According to favorable tax consideration
Make motion
All right
Thank you
I have a night team discussing
Disposition of county and city surface
Direct properties
All start on this one if i could
And that's why
Don't think the thing is to be long discussion
Since we don t had full council here tonight
But it s something
We just wanted
To bring up since
We've finished this
I want to thank Christo
Because she has done
And we are the county has
That could potentially be developed
Now some cannot
Be develop there very much in a flood way you can t rebuild
But, but
We have number i think just today
Just to day
We went over about 60 lots
That it coudn't actually be redeveloped
Again working with
The County summer city lawns
What would like
To eventually do and work with Christo
And it is that some of these lots
We like to have programs much
Much liked you just approve
That we might do on a smaller scale
If i had developed this
It may be one or two
To give them incentives and try
Get the board back up again
So if anybody s watching tonight
Seeing they were working with us
One entity on this
And then fill as has been identified by the
Compland
We can start bringing our housing
Housing inventory back up again
It s going to be one step at a time
But we just wanted
To let you know and have
A discussion maybe it
Atlatertime in
A lot greater detail about what
What i think is
You t are doing tonight
Is to just start having that discussion
We re trying
To get this ship turned around as i was quoted last night
Not a whole lot more
Again, the snow book
I hate calling it a snow book
It s one of those huge three ring binders
With over 60 tabs
Document
What we understand
Of all
We have been on our own properties
And we ve
We've been slowly and gradually evaluating all of them
To determine for example may or
For the floodplains status
Those are separately charter
They still
Have use in redevelopment
In a city of mind, some floodplain
Plain property is maybe available
In a city of mind, some floodplain property
With regard to the
We call it the non-flood plain properties
As is
As a City manager mentioned in this morning
We had a meeting this evening
And went through over 60
Of those
Met with
And others, to simply look at visual displays
Of each one of these properties
To determine their size
Their status
What we knew about it in terms
In addition
To help develop recommendations
To bring back the council
For purposes a future communication with
The county commissioners and the dean said
We spoke with Commission and Russell Orals
And again, should the council decide
To accept
Request and accept
Some are all of these lots from
The county. Yes there is a legal mechanism to do that
There's so many options
You can go
They're maybe instances in which
That best utilization
Of certain properties may simply be for
For the neighbors
In county to most of the properties
There may be available for additional
Construction. If structures that
Maybe are able
To remodel or renovated, you will
Be in position
And different
We're still developing the packages
For the public and say,
To go into
The public and say,
To do that,
If you're able to
Be in the interest of
The community and the community
We want
To be an opposition
A very steady pace
And even if root 66
Landing is successful
There could
Be a face-tooth
We identified numerous lots
That are essentially vacant
Lots right now owned by the county
Which could be conveyed to
The city which it appears
To us, can we build on?
Well
For me as a company and
To control our destiny, to go forward
Making informed decisions
And not just have hazard
Decisions. It's what that
At times done
We're not going to be
To make it clear
If there's no
I'm involved on that
Just really information
From an informational standpoint
And also
To introduce this concept, the city attorney
Just indicated
Every lot is gonna have its own story
And we're going to be a
We hope that there will have other people
That would do with this as well
It could
To communicate
About where those lots are located
I think one of the things
Probably social media probably working
Our local media, stories about them
The article was on KOM last night
They can host a great way
We also are working on those solutions
Can we get a map somewhere
There if you have to go, reflect
On the website
Okay
Thank You
I'm 20 is contract for purchase of real property
A 200-E speed J tunnel, being that has your name
Yes
Well again this
Another project in relationship
To control our own destiny
To work with the trustee
That owns that gopitch of property
And we have come to a very quickly
We came
Recommendation for you about real estate purchase
It's $65,000
For this property
I believe
The trustee has accepted
We currently
Check chestnut working on the title
And doing the basic title
I think trustee wants to have everything
Data about January 11
From their point of view they are working on that
Also in your packet we did
We give you a review
Of this one environmental
A lot questions
Other things
But nothing was surprised
In fact what
We have a lot of money
That's what we are going to do
And this property
Once it is demolished, could be reused
So once you get the whole thing
Obviously working with ODQ
To give into brownfields program
To take them down
A number things that
Possibly this is long-term planning
But probably a great location for
A new fire station or community
We could redevelop
Part of it into private development
If we want to through the brownfields program
It has been cost effective
To buy that and take
So I think at
This point, if you will give me permission
That
And get this in our inventory
The purchase price of 65,000
Then they will be some associated closing costs
There would so the original proposal
Was that you gave me permission up to 70
So I have about 5 000
That is what it takes care
It's sort
Of a standard allocation
It has been a very
Standard real estate transaction
It has been a very low amount of money
So I will give you one person
That is standard for
We have an heavily gotten down
Okay, so all we need to do
A motion two at the contract
Yes
I'll make that Motion 2
Second
I'm sorry
Well, hello
Thank You
I am 21 new business
No, not on this agenda
Okay staff reports are in your packet
If there is no questions we will move onto mayor and council
All right one question
And Tyler probably knows coming
Going out to bed
That's a joke question
that has been a joke
Yeah
This figure point
Yes, it was my morning
Okay
To open the end
So we got a few questions
We want this to be
Last time, I opened it on this one
Turn up
Councilman Johnson was going about win
Asked every week
I mean in those cries
Yeah, what is Monday again
The project team
There's a number of people still
We wrap up everything Monday and get out of this
Okay, thank you
City members communication
Two items one Tyler asked me to report that the phase two
Of The Southwest Waterwell is getting underway
There will be times with part
This project but people in
That area we'll have water pressure
Will notifying them when it happens
But this wrap-up
That's what it did now
The second thing is there are a lot of people
To thank for their hard work during the
Reset storms in high water events
Especially I'd like to mention
Lendough course our dispatch crew was phenomenal
Police and fires, always great public works did
It worked at a large job
This time Water came up high enough that we took
We took the pumps out
So those were preserved
A lot more work but its done
It was reported that when you have high water events like this
This has a big effect on our wastewater treatment plant
And are people really on top of it
I'm sure forgotten some
People and i do not intend to but
You got good staff
When the event is there's another
Another event too, just wanted
A lot more work, yes
That course
Okay
If nothing else
Okay, do we have a motion to adjourn you?
Motion to adjourned by the
Second
All right
Thank y'all
I'm gonna get you out of here
That's
Recently one more loss